Alfred Terhune Collection Relating to Edward FitzGerald
Alfred Terhune Collection relating to Edward FitzGerald
- Terhune correspondence-subject files
  - Houghton, Walter Edwards, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Hussey, Frank, 1959-1975; 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Hussey, Frank, photographic enclosures, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Kerrich, John E. and Sigrid, 1958-1969 (Box 10)
  - Kerrich, Mary Eleanor FitzGerald and Olivia, 1936-1951 (Box 10)
  - Kerrich, Walter and Frieda, 1951-1963 (Box 10)
  - Lingwood, Harold Robert, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
  - Loder, Violet, 1957-1969 (Box 10)
  - Low, David, 1936 (Box 10)
  - Maas, Waldo, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Macmillan Company, 1938-1956 (Box 10)
  - Mayfield, John S., 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Morfey, Wallace Mortimer, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Munby, Alan Noel Latimer, 1969-1970 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper query answers, 1936-1939 (Box 10)
  - Pope-Hennessy, James, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Bernard Quaritch (firm), 1934-1964 (Box 10)
  - Scarfe, Norman, 1968-1978 (Box 10)
  - Spalding, Gerald, 1936 (Box 10)
  - Syracuse University Libraries, 1956-1975 (Box 10)
  - Thomas, Denis, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Thomas Thorpe (bookseller), 1962-1965 (Box 10)
  - Charles W. Traylen (bookseller), 1957-1961 (Box 10)
  - Trinity College (University of Cambridge), 1939-1956 (Box 10)
  - Victorian Studies, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Watson, R. L., 1936-1939 (Box 10)
  - Weber, Carl Jefferson, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Weeks, Edward, 1938-1939 (Box 10)
  - Wilton, Harry E., 1966-1972 (Box 10)
- Terhune writings
  - "Edward FitzGerald: a Biography" Vol. 1 (Box 10)
  - "Edward FitzGerald: a Biography" Vol. 2 (Box 11)
  - Letters of Edward FitzGerald manuscript, final carbon
    - FitzGerald chronology (Box 11)
    - Biographical profiles, 2 foldes (Box 11)
    - Index of letters, 1867-1883 (Box 11)
    - Letters, 1830-1840; 11 folders (Box 11)
    - Letters, 1841-1848; 10 folders (Box 12)
    - Letters, 1849-1857; 11 folders (Box 13)
    - Letters, 1858-1867; 13 folders (Box 14)
    - Letters, 1868-1873 Jun; 12 folders (Box 15)
    - Letters, 1873 Jul-1877 Jun; 8 folders (Box 16)
    - Letters, 1877 Jul-1881 Mar; 12 folders (Box 17)
    - Letters, 1881 Apr-1883 Jun; 8 folders (Box 18)
    - Epilogue (Box 18)
- Terhune research notes
  - Allen, John (Box 18)
  - Allen, Matthew (Box 18)
  - Barton, Bernard (Box 18)
  - Barton, Lucy (Box 18)
  - Beccles (England) research (Box 18)
  - Bibliographical notes, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Biographical data (various) (Box 18)
  - Boston Public Library, FitzGerald-related material, photostats with transcriptions and annotations (Box 18)
  - Browning, Robert (Box 19)
  - Carlyle, Thomas (Box 19)
  - Churchyard, Thomas (Box 19)
  - Constable, Thomas (Box 19)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Crabbe, Mary (Box 19)
  - De Soyres material (Box 19)
  - East Anglia (England) (Box 19)
  - Edward, Edwin (Mrs.) (Box 19)
  - FitzGerald, Edward
    - Articles about (Box 19)
    - Early life and college years, 5 folders (Box 19)
    - Family and genealogical material, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Homes, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Later years, investments, Woodbridge anecdotes (Box 20)
    - Library (Box 20)
    - Manuscripts and books at Trinity College (University of Cambridge) (Box 20)
    - Music and miscellaneous verse (original), 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Passages about (Box 20)
    - Persian studies (Box 20)
    - Pictures (artworks) (Box 20)
    - Possessions, miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Reminiscences by others (Box 20)
    - Reviews, American, photocopies (Box 20)
    - Reviews, British, photocopies (Box 20)
    - Reviews of works and general criticism (Box 20)
    - Scrapbooks, notes (Box 20)
    - Translation, notes on, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Watermarks, ink, paper (Box 20)
  - FitzGerald and Omar references (Box 20)
  - FitzGerald, Lucy Barton, See Barton, Lucy.
  - Fletcher, Joseph (Box 20)
  - Ganz, Charles, Trinity College, Cambridge (Box 20)
  - Gasker, Athanasius (Box 20)
  - Hockley, W. B. (Box 20)
  - Holyoake, George Jacob (Box 20)
  - Ipswich Library, FitzGerald-related material (Box 20)
  - Keene, Charles (Box 20)
  - Kemble, Fanny (Box 21)
  - Kemble Family (Box 21)
  - Kerrich, Annie / Wright, William Aldis, correspondence, transcripts (Box 21)
  - Kerrich, Mary Eleanor FitzGerald, articles and notes (Box 21)
  - Maas, Waldo, Maas collection notes; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Mayfield, John S. (Box 21)
  - Milnes, R. M. (Box 21)
  - Morton, Savile, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Naseby (battlefield) material (Box 21)
  - 19th century periodicals (Box 21)
  - Nursey, Marietta (Box 21)
  - Omariana (Box 21)
  - Omar's grave and Omar's rose (Box 21)
  - Pasifull, Ablett (Box 21)
  - Pendleton Colliery, prospectus and notes; Robert Stephenson correspondence, transcripts (Box 21)
  - Pollock, William Frederick (Box 21)
  - Posh, See Fletcher, Joseph.
  - Quaritch, Bernard (Box 21)
  - Rubaiyat centennial celebration, miscellaneous items to commemorate the 100th anniversary of the publication of Edward FitzGerald's translation of The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam, Syracuse University (Box 21)
  - Rubaiyat centennial celebration, miscellaneous items to commemorate the 100th anniversary of the publication of Edward FitzGerald's translation of The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam, George Arents Research Library at Syracuse University (Box 22)
  - Rubaiyat collection owned by Miss Helen Jewett ... bequeathed to the State University of New York at Cortland (Box 22)
  - Rubaiyat discovery controversy, Weber material (Box 22)
  - Rubaiyat market values (Box 22)
  - Rubaiyat, miscellaneous notes, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Ruskin, John (Box 22)
  - Singleton, Henry, artwork (Box 22)
  - Spalding, Frederick (Box 22)
  - Spedding, James (Box 22)
  - Spedding James / Thompson, W. H., correspondence (Box 22)
  - Stephenson, Robert, See Pendleton Colliery.
  - Suffolk (England) maps, one photocopy, small; one hand-drawn, large; 2 items (Box 22)
  - Suffolk (England) maps, one printed; one hand-drawn with pasted-on labels; 2 items
  - Suffolk (England), parish registers (Box 22)
  - Suffolk (England), notes and printed material (Box 22)
  - Swinburne, A. C., 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Syracuse University, FitzGerald-related material; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Tennyson, Alfred (Box 23)
  - Tennyson, Frederick (Box 23)
  - Thackeray, Anne (Box 23)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Thompson, W. H., See Spedding, James / Thompson, W. H. correspondence
  - Tichborne case (Box 23)
  - University of Virginia, FitzGerald-related material, carbons and notes (Box 23)
  - Weber, Carl J., See Rubaiyat discovery controversy
  - Wheeler bibliography (Box 23)
  - Wilson, Henry Schutz (Box 23)
  - Yohannan, John D., Persian scholarship in England (Box 23)
  - Clippings (Box 23)
  - FitzGerald and related letters, Arents Library, copies (Box 23)
  - FitzGerald letters, miscellaneous recipients, "inconsequential", transcripts (Box 23)
  - FitzGerald letters with Persian text, 1854-1856; 6 folders (Box 23)
  - FitzGerald letters with Persian text, 1857-1868; 10 folders (Box 24)
  - Frontispiece from Letters and Literary Remains, W. Aldis Wright (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous copies of letters, notes, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous copies of letters, notes, 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Notes on Epilogue, Appendices for The Letters of Edward FitzGerald (Box 24)
  - Notes on illustrations (Box 24)
  - Notes on illustrations (cont.), 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Persian passages notes (Box 25)
  - Research expenses (Box 25)
  - Slides (Box 25)
  - Microfilm index [I-III], 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Microfilm Index [IV], Lowell and Norton indices (Box 25)
  - Microfilm Index [V], Pollock Index (Box 25)
  - Microfilm Index [VI], Spring Rice Index (Box 25)
  - Microfilm Index to F. Tennyson (Box 25)
  - Microfilm index, smaller films (Box 25)
  - Unidentified partial manuscript (Box 25)
  - Research notes on index cards, 8 cardfiles (Box 26, 27)
  - Maps of England, one-inch ordnance maps of Birmingham, Keswick, Ipswich, Carmarthen, etc.; quarter-inch ordnance map of East Anglia; London city maps, road maps of England and Wales, etc.; 38 items (Box 28)
- Microfilm index
  - Kemble, Fanny (Source: British Museum-originals) (Reel 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Source: British Museum) (Reel 1)
  - Neg. of 001 (Source: British Museum) (Reel 2)
  - Kemble, Fanny (Source: British Museum-transcripts) (Reel 3)
  - Neg. of 003 (Source: British Museum-transcripts) (Reel 4)
  - Spalding Frederick (Source: Brown Univ., Koopman Collection) (Reel 5)
  - Biddell, Anna (Source: Brown Univ., Koopman Collection) (Reel 5)
  - Neg. of 005 (Source: Brown Univ., Koopman Collection) (Reel 6)
  - Brooke, Francis Capper (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 7)
  - Byron's lines an Rogers (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 7)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 7)
  - Neg. of 007 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 8)
  - Calcutta ms. (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 9)
  - Neg. of 009 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 10)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles v.1 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 11)
  - Neg. of 012 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 12)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles v.2 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 13)
  - Neg. of 014 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 14)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles v.3 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 15)
  - Neg. of 015 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 16)
  - Naseby letters to trustees about monument (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 17)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 17)
  - Neg. of 017 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 18)
  - Ousely ms. (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 19)
  - Neg. of 019 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 20)
  - Pollock, William Frederick (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 21)
  - Neg. of 021 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 22)
  - Spalding, Frederick (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 23)
  - Neg. of 023 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 24)
  - Spring-Rice, Stephen (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 25)
  - Neg. of 025 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 26)
  - Tennyson, Alfred (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 27)
  - Tennyson, Frederick (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 28)
  - Neg. of 029 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 29)
  - Donne letters, Mrs Johnson (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 29)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace (Source: ?) (Reel 30)
  - Dickinson, Anne (Mrs.) (Source: ?) (Reel 30)
  - Neg. of 030 (Source: ?) (Reel 31)
  - Fitzwilliam Museum Papers (Source: Fitzwilliam Museum) (Reel 32)
  - Neg. of 032 (Source: Fitzwilliam Museum) (Reel 33)
  - extra neg. copy of 032 (Source: Fitzwilliam Museum) (Reel 34)
  - Norton, Charles Eliot (Source: Harvard) (Reel 35)
  - Lowell, James Russell (Source: Harvard) (Reel 35)
  - Neg. of 035 (Source: Harvard) (Reel 36)
  - Spalding, Frederick (Source: Morgan Library) (Reel 37)
  - Basham (Source: Morgan Library) (Reel 37)
  - miscellaneous (Source: Morgan Library) (Reel 37)
  - Neg. of 037 (Source: Morgan Library) (Reel 38)
  - Donne letters, Mrs. Johnson (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 39)
  - Neg. of 039 (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 40)
  - Tennyson, Alfred, Ist part (Source: Cambridge University Library) (Reel 40)
  - Thackeray, Anne (Source: University of London) (Reel 41)
  - Neg. of 041 (Source: University of London) (Reel 42)
  - Thackeray, Anne, faulty film (Source: University of London) (Reel 43)
  - Tennyson, Alfred (outgoing) (Source: Tennyson estate) (Reel 44)
  - Tennyson, Alfred (incoming) (Source: Tennyson estate) (Reel 44)
  - Tennyson, Frederick (Source: Tennyson estate) (Reel 45)
  - Tennyson, Alfred (to EFG) (Source: Tennyson estate) (Reel 45)
  - EFG's notebook (Source: Tennyson estate (?)) (Reel 45)
  - Donne, W. B. (Source: Mrs. Johnson (?)) (Reel 46)
  - Allen, John, diary 1830 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 47)
  - Wright, W. A. (Source: Trinity) (Reel 47)
  - Neg. of 047 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 48)
  - Allen, John, diary 1831 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 49)
  - Neg. of 049 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 50)
  - Allen, John (Source: Trinity) (Reel 51)
  - Neg. of 051 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 52)
  - Thackeray, W. M. to EFG (Source: Trinity) (Reel 52)
  - Carlyle, Thomas, Naseby L1. (Source: Trinity) (Reel 53)
  - Neg. of 053 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 54)
  - Milnes, Richard Monckton (Source: Trinity) (Reel 55)
  - Neg. of 055 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 56)
  - Morton, Savile (Source: Trinity) (Reel 57)
  - Neg. of 057 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 58)
  - Tennyson, Alfred-Examiner Poemes (Source: Trinity ) (Reel 59)
  - EFG, Sea Slanq notebook (Source: Trinity) (Reel 59)
  - EFG, Sea Words, 1869 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 59)
  - EFG, Sea Words, 1870 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 59)
  - Neg. of 059 (Source: Trinity) (Reel 60)
  - Wright, William Aldis (Source: Trinity) (Reel 61)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles (Source: Trinity) (Reel 62)
  - Cowell, Elizabeth Charlesworth (Source: Trinity) (Reel 62)
  - Thompson, William Hepworth (Source: Trinity) (Reel 62)
  - Charlesworth, Mrs. (Source: Trinity) (Reel 62)
  - Carlyle, Thomas (Source: Trinity) (Reel 62)
  - Vis. Marpeth's "Jasmine tree..." (Source: Trinity) (Reel 62)
  - Wright, William Aldis (Source: Trinity) (Reel 63)
  - Wright to B. Quaritch (Source: Trinity) (Reel 64)
  - Quaritch, Bernard (Source: Trinity) (Reel 64)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles to EFG (Source: Trinity) (Reel 64)
  - Crabbe, George (Source: Trinity) (Reel 65)
  - Thompson, William Hepworth (Source: Trinity) (Reel 66)
  - miscellaneous (Source: Trinity) (Reel 66)
  - Cowell, Edward Byles (Source: Trinity) (Reel 67)
  - Cowell, Elizabeth Charlesworth (Source: Trinity) (Reel 67)
  - Borrow, George (Source: Trinity) (Reel 67)
  - Charlesworth, Mrs. (Source: Trinity) (Reel 67)
  - Kemble, Fanny (Source: Trinity) (Reel 68)
  - Stephen, Leslie (Source: Trinity) (Reel 68)
  - Woolner, Thomas (Source: Trinity) (Reel 68)
  - Kemble, Mrs. (Source: Trinity) (Reel 68)
  - Groom, Robert W. to EFG (Source: Trinity) (Reel 68)
  - Crabbe, George (French letters) (Source: Trinity) (Reel 69)
  - Wright, William Aldis (Source: Trinity) (Reel 69)
  - miscellaneous (Source: Trinity) (Reel 69)
  - Crabbe, George (French letters) (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Crowfoot (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Crabbe, George (English letters) (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Thompson, William Hepworth (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Stephen, Leslie (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Kemble, Fanny (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Hall, FitzEdward (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Ruskin, John, note (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Cowell, Edward B. & Elizabeth (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - miscellaneous (Source: Trinity) (Reel 70)
  - Fletcher, Joseph (Source: University of Texas at Austin) (Reel 71)
  - Neg. of 071 (Source: University of Texas at Austin) (Reel 72)
  - Barton, Bernard (Source: University of Virginia) (Reel 73)
  - Neg. of 074 (Source: University of Virginia) (Reel 74)
  - Biddell, Herman (Source: Yale University) (Reel 75)
  - Tennyson, Alfred (Source: Yale University) (Reel 75)
  - Groome, Francis Hindes (Source: Yale University) (Reel 75)
  - Fletcher, Joseph (Source: Yale University) (Reel 75)
  - Commonplace book (Source: Yale University) (Reel 75)
  - Neg. of 075 (Source: Yale University) (Reel 76)
Selected index to Edward FitzGerald associates' letters
Airy, Osmund15 May 1928 11 June 1928
Airy, W.9 Feb. 1864
Barrett, E.7 Aug. 1883
Barton, Bernard20 May 1841 8 June 1846 undated
Biddell, Amy (recipient)22 Oct. 1902 15 May 1928
Biddell, Anna9 Feb. 1864 (recipient) 25 June 1883 21 July 1883 5 June 1902 (recipient) 4 Jan. 1897 22 Oct. 1902 8 June 1905 22 May 1906 8 Jan. 1909 undated
Biddell, Arthur (recipient)undated
Biddell, Dorothea (recipient)11 June 1928
Biddell, Herman25 June 1883 (recipient) 21 July 1883 (recipient) 7 Aug. 1889 (recipient) 13 Nov. 1893 (recipient) 29 Jan. 1894 (recipient) 4 Jan. 1897 (recipient) 15 Apr. 1899 (recipient) 24 Sept.1900 (recipient) 16 Nov. 1900 (recipient) 12 Sept.1901 (recipient) 8 June 1905 (recipient) 22 May 1906 (recipient) 8 Jan. 1909 (recipient) 13 Feb. 1909 19 Apr. 1909 (recipient) 11 July 1910 undated (2)
Biddell, Jane (recipient)20 May 1846
Biddell, Miss (recipient)1910 (Terhune note)
Biddell, Mrs. (recipient)24 July 1943
Brooke, Francis Capper (recipient)20 June 1877 (?) 4 June 1883 12 June 1883 16 June 1883 17 June 1883 18 June 1883 20 June 1883 20 June 1883 21 June 1883 27 June 1883
Brooke, Francis Capper (recipient)9 July 1883 13 July 1883 7 Aug. 1883 9 Aug. 1883 15 Sept.1883 3 Dec. 1883
Burrage, Charles Dana (recipient)29 Mar. 1904
Corrance, C. T. (?)4 June 1883 12 June 1883 20 June 1883
Cowell, Edward Bylesbefore 8 July 1901 8 July 1901
Cowell, Mary24 July 1943 20 Oct. 1943
Crabbe, George8 June 1846 16 June 1883 21 June 1883 9 July 1883 13 July 1883 15 Sept.1883
Doughty, Ernest G.20 June 1883 9 Aug. 1883 3 Dec. 1883? 2 Dec. 1887 (recipient)
FitzGerald, Lucy Barton8 Jan. 1864 24 Feb. 1865
Hall, FitzEdward20 June 1877
Kerrich, Annie1910 (Terhune note) undated
Kerrich, Edmund17 June 1883 30 Nov. 1884 1 Dec. 1884 (recipient)
Kerrich, Lt. Col. (recipient)30 Nov. 1887
Lister, Henry Bertram (recipient)18 Apr. 1935
Loder, John6 Sept.1880 11 Sept.1901 12 Sept.1901 19 Nov. 1902 (recipient) 19 Apr. 1909 11 July 1910
Maas, Waldo (recipient)20 Oct. 1943
Miller, Dewitt (recipient)17 Apr. 1895
Moor, A. P. (recipient)14 June 1889
Moor, E. Charles15 Apr. 1899
Moor, George18 June 1883 29 Nov. 1884 (recipient) 30 Nov. 1884 (recipient) 1 Dec. 1884 6 Dec. 1884 (recipient) 8 Dec. 1884 (recipient) 2 Nov. 1887 (recipient) 11 Dec. 1887 (recipient)
Nicholson, Reynold Alleyne25 June 1923 28 Aug. 1923
Pasifull, Ablett19 Nov. 1902
Potter, Ambrose G. 18 Apr. 1935
Quaritch, Bernard29 Nov. 1884 6 Dec. 1884 8 Dec. 1884 2 Nov. 1887
Rees, R. Wilkins (recipient)before July 8 1901 8 July 1901
Ridding, Caroline Mary (recipient)25 June 1923 28 Aug. 1923
Smith, Alfred I.13 Nov. 1893 5 June 1902 undated
Turner, Ross Sterling29 Mar. 1904
Wright, W. Aldis27 June 1883 30 Nov. 1887 2 Dec. 1887 11 Dec. 1887 14 June 1889 7 Aug. 1889 29 Jan. 1894 7 May 1894 17 Apr. 1895 24 Sept.1900 16 Nov. 1900 11 Sept.1901 13 Feb. 1909 (recipient) (copy) 13 (?) Feb. 1909